Once you know what's required for success,
it's time for an honest self-assessment.
This is how you identify the gap
between where you are and where you want to be.
These gaps are not weaknesses.
They are opportunities.
They are specific areas you will target
in your 90-day plan.
Looking back at Lynn, her self-assessment was clear.
Mindset, check.
Motivation, check.
Legal experience, check.
Her gaps were in managing people, managing budgets,
and up-to-date industry knowledge.
So, her Make It Happen checklist
focused on closing those specific gaps.
These became her goals.
But a goal like getting better at managing budgets
is not a goal.
It's a wish.
To make it real, we use the SMART framework.
Now, I know many of you say,
I've heard of the SMART goals before.
But remember, this isn't about what you know
or what you've heard.
It's about what you do daily.
An Athleader applies these principles with discipline.
Your goal must be specific, measurable, attainable,
relevant, and time-bound.
Let's look at another example.
Evan is a CFO and a father of a son with autism.
His passion is to launch an online community
to support other parents of children with special needs.
One of the items on his gap checklist
was identifying a technical partner.
A SMART goal that became, within 60 days,
obtain partnership proposals from three qualified vendors
with each proposal detailing the creation
of a scalable online community that includes reporting,
functionality, and content self-management.
Do you see the difference?
It's specific, it's measurable, it's attainable,
it's relevant to his vision, and it's time-bound.
That is a goal you can execute against.
In your playbook, you will assess yourself
against the prerequisites you've identified.
Find your most critical gaps and then transform those gaps
into two or three powerful SMART goals
for your first 90-day season.